Alexander **Papiez**

Research Chemist

Contact

31 Ashfield Road Gosforth Newcastle Upon Tyne NE3 4XL

alex.papiez@gmail.com

Tel:07948373631

Key Skills

- 7 Years laboratory experience
- Tutoring experience
- · Competent user of LATEX typesetting software
- · Knowledge of the Python programming language
- Experienced user of Microsoft Office packages
- Able to work well independantly and in a group
- Excellent spelling and grammar
- Ability to work to a deadline/ under pressure

Profile

My attention and eye for detail have allowed me to be successful in my research career. As a self sufficient individual I have shown initiative in solving problems which have arisen promptly. In early 2016 I was invited to the International Congress on Marine Corrosion and Fouling in Toulon, France; where I presented aspects of my work to attendees. During the course of my studies I have consistently developed my ability to communicate ideas in a clear and concise manner while maintaining a engaging connection with the audience. I believe this is key to building rapports and successful working relationships.

Employment

09/2013-05/2016 Lab Demonstrator

Northumbria University

Worked to support the safe operation of lab-practical classes for undergraduate students. My knowledge in the field and previous experience with the course content meant I was able to act as an effective mentor and role model to students, helping to support the learning experience provided by the lead academic.

02/2015 - 05/2015 GCE A-Level Tutor (Chemistry)

Newcastle Upon Tyne

I provided one-to-one tutoring support to a student preparing to sit their chemistry A-Level exams. I developed a lesson plan for each session covering a specific topic to ensure that student was given the best opportunity to understand the content and succeed in the exams.

06/2013 - 09/2013 Production operative / Packer

Quorn Foods, Stokesley

I worked as part of a team on the Quorn production line. Duties included packing and palletizing the product, quality control, cleaning and some work in clean production areas.

Education

09/2013-Present PhD in Physical Polymer Chemistry

Northumbria University

Supervisors:	Dr. Justin Perry and Dr. Leslie Dix
Funded by:	AkzoNobel/International Paint
Thesis title:	Investigating the Rate of Release of Ions Across Polymer Phases
Summary:	In order to develop competitive products in a sustainable

ner, anti-fouling paint manufacturers must co kinetics of biocide release. By studying the diffusion rate of

biocides in relation to material properties, insights useful for the rational design of anti-fouling technologies may be found. Publications: Papiez, A.P. Perry, J.J.B Ferguson, J. Wright, A.C.

Diffusion of Biocides in Polymeric Matrices: A Tool for Rational

Coating Design, Poster presented at the International Congress on Marine Corrosion and Fouling, Toulon France, 2016;

Papiez, A.P. Perry, J.J.B. Downs, R.A. Design and Implementation of a 3D Printed Microwave Flow Cell, Poster presented at the R.S.C. Organic division meeting, Bradford, U.K. 2015

09/2009 - 06/2013 MChem Applied Chemistry

Northumbria University

Classification:	1st with honours
Awards:	Best Post-graduate final-year project, 2013
4th Year	Synthesis and Characterization of Amino Functionalized
Project:	Methacrylate Polymers
3rd Year Project:	Predicting Mass Spectra Using Density Functional Theory Calculations
-,	,

09/2007-07/2009 GCE A-Levels

Stokesley Sixth Form College

A2:	Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics
AS:	Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, French

09/2002-07/2007 GCSEs

Stokesley Comprehensive School

10 at grade A*-C including Maths, English and Science

Interests

I am a capable programmer and enjoy the creative thinking involved in solving technical problems; in conjunction with DIY electronics, I enjoy building software and hardware to tackle real world problems.

I am an avid reader - my favourite genre is historical non-fiction as I enjoy learning about the past and the lessons it holds for today's world. This spurs my interest in politics and current affairs, which I enjoy debating in great detail.

I love the operas of Gilbert and Sullivan, my favourites being The Mikado and Iolanthe. I am fascinated by the intricate combination of language and musical theatre which they employ to make clever satirical comments.

References

Dr. Justin Perry,

Enterprise Fellow

Health and Life Sciences

Dr. Leslie Dix,

Senior Lecturer,

Health and Life Sciences

Northumbria University,
Ellison Building,
Ellison Place,

Northumbria University,
Ellison Building,
Ellison Place,

Newcastle Upon Tyne, Newcastle Upon Tyne,

NE1 8ST, NE1 8ST,

Phone: 0191 227 3554, Phone: 0191 227 3510,

Email: justin.perry@northumbria.ac.uk Email: les.dix@northumbria.ac.uk

I have a full, clean U.K. driving licence and own a car.